<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Logan Lemieux</title>
    <description>Summary</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 23:03:23 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 23:03:23 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.0.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Creating a Website Using Jekyll in 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It seems odd to post to a blog in 2019. It’s like sending your voice out into a crowded street, using a pager from 1999. It doesn’t really work. Yet here I am, putting text into a jekyll theme to make that pager heard. I initially started this page upon a recommendation from a friend to a web development job that he convinced me I “totally had the skill for.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that I had no prior experience in web development, relatively little prior experience in coding (apart from a yearlong Python project in my senior year of high school), and no drive to create. Yet, within a week, I was exclusively running Manjaro Linux (a distro of Arch Linux) on my laptop, had a fully functional website set-up on github.io, and had complete belief in my ability to maintain it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I initially had very little idea of how to do this, having only very basic experience in HTML beforehand. My friend told me about jekyll, and while I was trying to install the required packages, he told me how much easier it was to do on Linux. I gave in and had him set me up a boot disk, and within an hour I had Manjaro running on my Surface Pro 6. Note that this didn’t come without issues–I didn’t know that Microsoft had BitLocker installed, so my entire Windows 10 partition was encrypted and subsequently lost. Fortunately, everything I could do on Windows 10 could be done almost exactly the same if not better on Manjaro. That included installing jekyll, which caused me more trouble than it should have on account of the fact that I was using an entirely new OS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as soon as it was installed, using it was a breeze. I found a template I liked (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gchauras/&quot;&gt;gchauras’ much-worse-jekyll-theme&lt;/a&gt;, cloned it to a my own github repository, and learned more about programming in 3 days than I had in the past 18 years. It surprised me how easy everything was–with a jekyll theme, I really didn’t have to do that much–it (for the most part, with some minor issues) magically turned markdown text into beautifully formatted CSS. Regardless, it got me into the mindset of programming–and it made me want to start working on other projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expect some more updates in the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With regards,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Logan Lemieux&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/11/12/creating-a-website-using-jekyll-in-2019</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/11/12/creating-a-website-using-jekyll-in-2019</guid>
        
        
        <category>tech</category>
        
        <category>thoughts</category>
        
        <category>coding</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
